{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Professional Issues in Information Systems and Technology",
    "Term": "Finals",
    "Title": "Finals Reviewer",
    "LastModified": "14 December 2024",
    "Authors": [
      "Elmer Felisilda"
    ],
    "References": [
      ""
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "This can help to contribute to society and human well-being.",
      "answer": "Minimizing the adverse effects of information systems",
      "choices": [
        "Minimizing the adverse effects of information systems",
        "Avoiding harm",
        "Being honest and trustworthy",
        "Finding Mary Grace Piattos"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is the act of obtaining or possessing another's identity and information to commit a legal offense.",
      "answer": "Identity Theft",
      "choices": [
        "Identity Theft",
        "Identity Fraud",
        "Phishing",
        "Cyberbullying"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following were the network developed during the first era of information systems?",
      "answer": "Mainframe and Minicomputers",
      "choices": [
        "Mainframe and Minicomputers",
        "Client and server",
        "Personal Computers",
        "SAP na laging may logical error"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "This deals with sharing technological knowledge and skills for underprivileged individuals.",
      "answer": "Pro Bono Publico",
      "choices": [
        "Pro Bono Publico",
        "Internet Safety",
        "Human Safety",
        "Environment and Sustainability"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following ensures that a reliable copy of the data is always available?",
      "answer": "Safety",
      "choices": [
        "Safety",
        "Accessibility",
        "Privacy",
        "Kavougability"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following ensures that a reliable copy of the data is always available?",
      "answer": "Safety",
      "choices": [
        "Safety",
        "Security",
        "Privacy",
        "Kavougability"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following deals with proper management and expression of emotions?",
      "answer": "Emotional Intelligence",
      "choices": [
        "Emotional Intelligence",
        "Creative Problem Solving",
        "Layoffs",
        "Therapy"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "This responsibility is the obligation to counter and disprove any false views related to the systems?",
      "answer": "Improve public understanding of computing and its consequences",
      "choices": [
        "Improve public understanding of computing and its consequences",
        "Honor contracts, agreements, and assigned responsibilities",
        "Acquire and maintain professional competence",
        "Access computing and communication resources only when authorized to do so"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of hte following ensures that backup data is an exact and unmodified copy of the original?",
      "answer": "Authenticity",
      "choices": [
        "Authenticity",
        "Safety",
        "Accessibility",
        "Security"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which startup recycles plastic waste into bricks that are resistant to water, fire, and heat?",
      "answer": "Brickify",
      "choices": [
        "Brickify",
        "Dryad Networks",
        "Start it Up! Get, Get, Ow!",
        "Brick Systems"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following ensures user modifications of online experiences to meet their preferences?",
      "answer": "Personal",
      "choices": [
        "Personal",
        "Wearable",
        "Printable",
        "Autonomous"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a challenge when professionals feel discouraged and demotivated?",
      "answer": "Low employee motivation",
      "choices": [
        "Low employee motivation",
        "Low pay",
        "Low 13th month pay",
        "Pinasayaw sa Christmas party kasi new hire"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following facilitate virtual or co-located meetings and manage group activities?",
      "answer": "Collaboration Management Tools",
      "choices": [
        "Collaboration Management Tools",
        "Electronic Conferencing Tools",
        "Electronic Communication Tools",
        "Online means"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is an ethical theory where individuals are accountable for fulfilling a civic duty.",
      "answer": "Social Responsibility",
      "choices": [
        "Social Responsibility",
        "Human Safety",
        "Ethical Responsibility",
        "Internet Safety"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following concerns the replacement of employees with more advanced computers?",
      "answer": "Lack of Job Security",
      "choices": [
        "Lack of Job Security",
        "Cost",
        "Security Issues",
        "A.I. uprising"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "These are integrated elements that gather, process, and dissiminate information.",
      "answer": "Information Systems",
      "choices": [
        "Information Systems",
        "Traditional Applications",
        "Advanced Applications",
        "Technology"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following encourages taking high-risk challenges as worries about reputation are non-existent?",
      "answer": "Confidence",
      "choices": [
        "Confidence",
        "Conscientiousness",
        "Competence",
        "Emotional Intelligence"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Social Responsibility is not ethically validated before taking action. (TR or FL)",
      "answer": "FL",
      "choices": [
        "FL",
        "TR"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following aims to resolve internet safety issues in information systems and technology?",
      "answer": "Applying lawful and stricter rules to systems",
      "choices": [
        "Applying lawful and stricter rules to systems",
        "Pro Bono Publico",
        "Share knowledge and skills in technology",
        "Immerse"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "These are part of personal trends in information systems and technology.",
      "answer": "Netflix's Algorithm",
      "choices": [
        "Drones / Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs)",
        "Netflix's Algorithm",
        "Smart Watches",
        "3D Printing"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which era of information systems and technology were centralized and concerned solely with governance?",
      "answer": "First Era",
      "choices": [
        "First Era",
        "Second Era",
        "Third Era",
        "Fourth Era"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "These secures a computer system by removing malware.",
      "answer": "Antivirus",
      "choices": [
        "Antivirus",
        "Cryptography",
        "Biometrics",
        "Phishing Detection"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which era of information systems and technology were centralized and concerned solely with governance?",
      "answer": "First Era",
      "choices": [
        "First Era",
        "Second Era",
        "Third Era",
        "Fourth Era"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is considered a characteristic of toxic work culture?",
      "answer": "Hiring someone \"culturally fit\"",
      "choices": [
        "Hiring someone \"culturally fit\"",
        "Unethical leadership",
        "\"Group think\" mentality",
        "Unrealistic deadlines ops sino yon"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following ensures that backup data is an exact and unmodified copy of the original?",
      "answer": "Authenticity",
      "choices": [
        "Authenticity",
        "Safety",
        "Accessibility",
        "Security"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following ensures that backup data is an exact and unmodified copy of the original?",
      "answer": "Authenticity",
      "choices": [
        "Authenticity",
        "Safety",
        "Accessibility",
        "Security"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is decrypted using decryption keys.",
      "answer": "Encrypted data / Ciphertext",
      "choices": [
        "Encrypted data / Ciphertext",
        "Plaintext",
        "Decrypted data",
        "Blowfish"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Deliberately creating false and misleading claims about a system can be considered as ethically responsible. (TR or FL)",
      "answer": "FL",
      "choices": [
        "FL",
        "TR"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can form and change the culture?",
      "answer": "Technology",
      "choices": [
        "Technology",
        "Security",
        "Technological Trends",
        "Societal Changes"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Technology can form and change the culture. (TR or FL)",
      "answer": "TR",
      "choices": [
        "TR",
        "FL"
      ],
      "reference": "Finals Review",
      "term": "Finals"
    }
  ]
}